<div type="bib">
    <head>References</head>
    <listBibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl1">A. Berger and V. Mittal. 2000. OCELOT: A system for summarizing Web Pages. In Proceedings of SIGIR2000.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl2">K. Barker and N. Cornacchia. 2000. Using nounphrase heads to extract document keyphrases. In Canadian Conference on AI.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl3">O. Buyukkokten, H. Garcia-Molina, and A. Paepcke. 2001. Seeing the whole in parts: text summarization for web browsing on handheld devices. In Proceedings of WWW2001.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl4">M. Chen, J.-T. Sun, H.-J. Zeng and K.-Y. Lam. 2005. A practical system for keyphrase extraction for web pages. In Proceedings of CIKM2005.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl5">E. Frank, G. W. Paynter, I. H. Witten, C. Gutwin, and C. G. Nevill-Manning. 1999. Domain-specific keyphrase extraction. Proceedings of IJCAI-99, pp. 668-673.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl6">C. Gutwin, G. W. Paynter, I. H. Witten, C. G. NevillManning and E. Frank. 1999. Improving browsing in digital libraries with keyphrase indexes. Journal of Decision Support Systems, 27, 81-104.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl7">K. M. Hammouda, D. N. Matute and M. S. Kamel. 2005. CorePhrase: keyphrase extraction for document clustering. In Proceedings of MLDM2005.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl8">A. Hulth. 2003. Improved automatic keyword extraction given more linguistic knowledge. In Proceedings of EMNLP2003, Japan, August.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl9">A. K. Jain, M. N. Murty and P. J. Flynn. 1999. Data clustering: a review. ACM Computing Surveys, 31(3):264-323.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl10">D. Kelleher and S. Luz. 2005. Automatic hypertext keyphrase detection. In Proceedings of IJCAI2005.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl11">B. Krulwich and C. Burkey. 1996. Learning user information interests through the extraction of semantically significant phrases. In AAAI 1996 Spring Symposium on Machine Learning in Information Access.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl12">O. Medelyan and I. H. Witten. 2006. Thesaurus based automatic keyphrase indexing. In Proceedings of JCDL2006.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl13">R. Mihalcea and P. Tarau. 2004. TextRank: Bringing order into texts. In Proceedings of EMNLP2004.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl14">A. Muñoz. 1996. Compound key word generation from document databases using a hierarchical clustering ART model. Intelligent Data Analysis, 1(1).</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl15">T. D. Nguyen and M.-Y. Kan. 2007. Keyphrase extraction in scientific publications. In Proceedings of ICADL2007.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl16">P. Over. 2001. Introduction to DUC-2001: an intrinsic evaluation of generic news text summarization systems. In Proceedings of DUC2001.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl17">L. Page, S. Brin, R. Motwani, and T. Winograd. 1998. The pagerank citation ranking: Bringing order to the web. Technical report, Stanford Digital Libraries.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl18">M. Song, I.-Y. Song and X. Hu. 2003. KPSpotter: a flexible information gain-based keyphrase extraction system. In Proceedings of WIDM2003.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl19">A. M. Steier and R. K. Belew. 1993. Exporting phrases: A statistical analysis of topical language. In Proceedings of Second Symposium on Document Analysis and Information Retrieval, pp. 179-190.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl20">T. Tomokiyo and M. Hurst. 2003. A language model approach to keyphrase extraction. In: Proceedings of ACL Workshop on Multiword Expressions.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl21">K. Toutanova and C. D. Manning. 2000. Enriching the knowledge sources used in a maximum entropy Part-ofSpeech tagger. In Proceedings of EMNLP/VLC-2000.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl22">P. D. Turney. 2000. Learning algorithms for keyphrase extraction. Information Retrieval, 2:303-336.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl23">P. D. Turney. 2003. Coherent keyphrase extraction via web mining. In Proc. of IJCAI-03, pages 434–439.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl24">X. Wan, J. Yang and J. Xiao. 2007a. Towards an iterative reinforcement approach for simultaneous document summarization and keyword extraction. In Proceedings of ACL2007.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl25">I. H. Witten, G. W. Paynter, E. Frank, C. Gutwin, and C. G. Nevill-Manning. 1999. KEA: Practical automatic keyphrase extraction. Proceedings of Digital Libraries 99 (DL'99), pp. 254-256.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl26">W.-T. Yih, J. Goodman and V. R. Carvalho. 2006. Finding advertising keywords on web pages. In Proceedings of WWW2006.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl27">H. Y. Zha. 2002. Generic summarization and keyphrase extraction using mutual reinforcement principle and sentence clustering. In Proceedings of SIGIR2002, pp. 113-120.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl28">Y. Zhang, N. Zincir-Heywood, and E. Milios. 2004. TermBased Clustering and Summarization of Web Page Collections. In Proceedings of the Seventeenth Conference of the Canadian Society for Computational Studies of Intelligence.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl29">Y. Zhang, N. Zincir-Heywood and E. Milios. 2005. Narrative text classification for automatic key phrase extraction in web document corpora. In Proceedings of WIDM2005.</bibl>
    </listBibl>
</div>
