<div type="bib">
    <head>References</head>
    <listBibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl1">Marti A. Hearst. 1992. Automatic Acquisition of Hyponyms from Large Text Corpora. COLING 92: (2) pp. 539-545, Nantes, France,</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl2">Frank Keller and Mirella Lapata. 2003. Using the Web to Obtain Frequencies for Unseen Bigrams. Computational Linguistics, 29: pp 459-484.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl3">Mirella Lapata and Frank Keller. 2005. Web-Based Models for Natural Language Processing. ACM Transactions on Speech and Language Processing 2:1, pp 1-31.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl4">Mark Lauer. 1995. Designing Statistical Language Learners: Experiments on Noun Compounds. PhD thesis, Macquarie University, NSW 2109, Australia.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl5">judith Levi. 1978. The Syntax and Semantics of Complex Nominals, Academic Press, New York, NY.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl6">Dan Moldovan, Adriana Badulescu, Marta Tatu, Daniel Antohe and Roxana Girju. 2004. Models for the Semantic Classification of Noun Phrases. In Proceedings of the HLTINAACL Workshop on Computational Lexical Semantics. pp 60-67 Boston , MA.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl7">Preslav Nakov and Marti Hearst. 2006. Using Verbs to Characterize Noun-Noun Relations. In Proceedings of AIMSA 2006, pp 233-244, Varne, Bulgaria.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl8">Preslav Nakov and Marti Hearst. 2005. Using the Web as an Implicit Training Set: Application to Structural Ambiguity Resolution. In Proceedings of HLTIEMNLP'0S. pp 835-842, Vancouver, Canada.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl9">Vivi Nastase and Stan Szpakowicz. 2003. Exploring Noun-Modifier Semantic Relations. In Fifth International Workshop on Computational Semantics, pp 285-301. Tillburg, Netherlands.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl10">Barbara Rosario and Marti A. Hearst. 2001. Classifying the semantic relations in noun compounds via a domain-specific lexical hierarchy. In Proceedings of EMNLP 2001, pp 82-90, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl11">Peter D. Turney. 2001. Mining the web for synonyms: PM-IR vs LSA on TOEFL. Proceedings of ECML'01. pp 491-502. Freiburg, Germany.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl12">Peter D. Turney and Michael L. Littman. 2005. Corpusbased learning of analogies and semantic relations. Machine Learning, 60(1-3):251-278.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl13">Ian H. Witten and Eibe Frank. 1999. Data Mining: Practical Machine Learning Tools and Techniques with Java Implementations. Morgan Kaufmann.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl14">George K. Zipf. 1932. Selected Studies of the Principle of Relative Frequency in Language. Cambridge, MA.</bibl>
    </listBibl>
</div>
