<div type="bib">
    <head>References</head>
    <listBibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl1">Sophia Ananiadou, Sampo Pyysalo, Junichi Tsujii, and Douglas B. Kell. 2010a. Event extraction for systems biology by text mining the literature. Trends in Biotechnology. (to appear).</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl2">M Ashburner, CA Ball, JA Blake, D Botstein, H Butler, JM Cherry, AP Davis, K Dolinski, SS Dwight, JT Eppig, MA Harris, DP Hill, L Issel-Tarver, A Kasarskis, S Lewis, JC Matese, JE Richardson, M Ringwald, GM Rubin, and G Sherlock. 2000. Gene ontology: tool for the unification of biology. Nature genetics, 25:25–29.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl3">Jari Bj¨orne, Juho Heimonen, Filip Ginter, Antti Airola, Tapio Pahikkala, and Tapio Salakoski. 2009. Extracting complex biological events with rich graphbased feature sets. In Proceedings of the BioNLP 2009 Workshop Companion Volume for Shared Task, pages 10–18, Boulder, Colorado, June. Association for Computational Linguistics.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl4">Chih-Chung Chang and Chih-Jen Lin, 2001. LIBSVM: a library for support vector machines. Software available at http://www.csie.ntu. edu.tw/˜cjlin/libsvm.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl5">Hong-Woo Chun, Yoshimasa Tsuruoka, Jin-Dong Kim, Rie Shiba, Naoki Nagata, Teruyoshi Hishiki, and Jun’ichi Tsujii. 2006. Extraction of genedisease relations from medline using domain dictionaries and machine learning. In Proceedings of the Pacific Symposium on Biocomputing (PSB’06), pages 4–15.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl6">Marie-Catherine de Marneffe, Bill MacCartney, and Christopher D. Manning. 2006. Generating Typed Dependency Parses from Phrase Structure Parses. In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC’06), pages 449–454.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl7">Mario Juhas, Derrick W. Crook, and Derek W. Hood. 2008. Type IV secretion systems: tools of bacterial horizontal gene transfer and virulence. Cellular microbiology, 10(12):2377–2386.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl8">Jin-Dong Kim, Tomoko Ohta, and Jun’ichi Tsujii. 2008. Corpus annotation for mining biomedical events fromlterature. BMC Bioinformatics,9(1):10.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl9">Jin-Dong Kim, Tomoko Ohta, Sampo Pyysalo, Yoshinobu Kano, and Jun’ichi Tsujii. 2009. Overview of BioNLP’09 Shared Task on Event Extraction. In Proceedings of Natural Language Processing in Biomedicine (BioNLP) NAACL 2009 Workshop, pages 1–9.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl10">Martin Krallinger, Florian Leitner, and Alfonso Valencia. 2007. Assessment of the Second BioCreative PPI task: Automatic Extraction of Protein-Protein Interactions. In L. Hirschman, M. Krallinger, and A. Valencia, editors, Proceedings of Second BioCreative Challenge Evaluation Workshop, pages 29–39.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl11">John D. Lafferty, Andrew McCallum, and Fernando C . N. Pereira. 2001. Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data. In ICML ’01: Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Machine Learning, pages 282–289.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl12">R. Leaman and G. Gonzalez. 2008. Banner: an executable survey of advances in biomedical named entity recognition. Pacific Symposium on Biocomputing, pages 652–663.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl13">David McClosky and Eugene Charniak. 2008. SelfTraining for Biomedical Parsing. In Proceedings of the 46th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics - Human Language Technologies (ACL-HLT’08), pages 101–104.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl14">Claire N´edellec. 2005. Learning Language in Logic - Genic Interaction Extraction Challenge. In J. Cussens and C. N´edellec, editors, Proceedings of the 4th Learning Language in Logic Workshop (LLL05), pages 31–37.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl15">Tomoko Ohta, Jin-Dong Kim, Sampo Pyysalo, and Jun’ichi Tsujii. 2009. Incorporating GENETAGstyle annotation to GENIA corpus. In Proceedings of Natural Language Processing in Biomedicine (BioNLP) NAACL 2009 Workshop, pages 106–107, Boulder, Colorado. Association for Computational Linguistics.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl16">Sampo Pyysalo, Filip Ginter, Juho Heimonen, Jari Bj¨orne, Jorma Boberg, Jouni J¨arvinen, and Tapio Salakoski. 2007. BioInfer: A corpus for information extraction in the biomedical domain. BMC Bioinformatics, 8(50).</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl17">Andrey Rzhetsky, Ivan Iossifov, Tomohiro Koike, Michael Krauthammer, Pauline Kra, Mitzi Morris, Hong Yu, Pablo Ariel Dubou´e, Wubin Weng, W. John Wilbur, Vasileios Hatzivassiloglou, and Carol Friedman. 2004. GeneWays: A system for extracting, analyzing, visualizing, and integrating molecular pathway data. Journal of Biomedical Informatics, 37(1):43–53.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl18">Lorraine Tanabe, Natalie Xie, Lynne Thom, Wayne Matten, and John Wilbur. 2005. Genetag: a tagged corpus for gene/protein named entity recognition. BMC Bioinformatics, 6(Suppl 1):S3.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl19">Paul Thompson, Syed Iqbal, John McNaught, and Sophia Ananiadou. 2009. Construction of an annotated corpus to support biomedical information extraction. BMC Bioinformatics, 10(1):349.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl20">Yue Wang, Jin-Dong Kim, Rune Saetre, Sampo Pyysalo, and Jun’ichi Tsujii. 2009. Investigating heterogeneous protein annotations toward crosscorpora utilization. BMCBioinformatics, 10(1):403.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl21">John Wilbur, Lawrence Smith, and Lorraine Tanabe. 2007. BioCreative 2. Gene Mention Task. In L. Hirschman, M. Krallinger, and A. Valencia, editors, Proceedings of Second BioCreative Challenge Evaluation Workshop, pages 7–16.</bibl>
    </listBibl>
</div>
