<div type="bib">
    <head>References</head>
    <listBibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl1">Omri Abend, Roi Reichart and Ari Rappoport, 2009. Unsupervised Argument Identification for Semantic Role Labeling. ACL ’09.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl2">Omri Abend, Roi Reichart and Ari Rappoport, 2010. Improved Unsupervised POSInduction through Prototype Discovery. ACL ’10.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl3">Timothy Baldwin, Valia Kordoni and Aline Villavicencio, 2009. Prepositions in Applications: A Survey and Introduction to the Special Issue. Computational Linguistics, 35(2):119–147.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl4">Ram Boukobza and Ari Rappoport, 2009. MultiWord Expression Identification Using Sentence Surface Features. EMNLP ’09.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl5">Leo Breiman, 1996. Bagging Predictors. Machine Learning, 24(2):123–140.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl6">Ted Briscoe and John Carroll, 1997. Automatic Extraction of Subcategorization from Corpora. Applied NLP ’97.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl7">Lou Burnard, 2000. User Reference Guide for the British National Corpus. Technical report, Oxford University.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl8">Xavier Carreras and Lluis M`arquez, 2005. Introduction to the CoNLL–2005 Shared Task: Semantic Role Labeling. CoNLL ’05.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl9">Alexander Clark, 2003. Combining Distributional and Morphological Information for Part of Speech Induction. EACL ’03.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl10">Michael Collins, 1999. Head-driven statistical models for natural language parsing. Ph.D. thesis, University of Pennsylvania.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl11">David Dowty, 2000. The Dual Analysis of Adjuncts and Complements in Categorial Grammar. Modifying Adjuncts, ed. Lang, Maienborn and Fabricius– Hansen, de Gruyter, 2003.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl12">Katrin Erk, 2007. A Simple, Similarity-based Model for Selectional Preferences. ACL ’07.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl13">Evgeniy Gabrilovich and Shaul Markovitch, 2005. Feature Generation for Text Categorization using World Knowledge. IJCAI ’05.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl14">David Graff, 1995. North American News Text Corpus. Linguistic Data Consortium. LDC95T21.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl15">Trond Grenager and Christopher D. Manning, 2006. Unsupervised Discovery of a Statistical Verb Lexicon. EMNLP ’06.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl16">Donald Hindle and Mats Rooth, 1993. Structural Ambiguity and Lexical Relations. Computational Linguistics, 19(1):103–120.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl17">Julia Hockenmaier, 2003. Data and Models for Statistical Parsing with Combinatory Categorial Grammar. Ph.D. thesis, University of Edinburgh.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl18">Karin Kipper, Hoa Trang Dang and Martha Palmer, 2000. Class-Based Construction of a Verb Lexicon. AAAI ’00.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl19">Hang Li and Naoki Abe, 1998. Generalizing Case Frames using a Thesaurus and the MDL Principle. Computational Linguistics, 24(2):217–244.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl20">Wei Li, Xiuhong Zhang, Cheng Niu, Yuankai Jiang and Rohini Srihari, 2003. An Expert Lexicon Approach to Identifying English Phrasal Verbs. ACL ’03.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl21">Dekang Lin, 1998. Automatic Retrieval and Clustering of Similar Words. COLING–ACL ’98.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl22">Ken Litkowski and Orin Hargraves, 2005. The Preposition Project. ACL-SIGSEM Workshop on “The Linguistic Dimensions of Prepositions and Their Use in Computational Linguistic Formalisms and Applications”.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl23">Diana McCarthy, 2001. Lexical Acquisition at the Syntax-Semantics Interface: Diathesis Alternations, Subcategorization Frames and Selectional Preferences. Ph.D. thesis, University of Sussex.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl24">Paula Merlo and Eva Esteve Ferrer, 2006. The Notion of Argument in Prepositional Phrase Attachment. Computational Linguistics, 32(3):341–377.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl25">Martha Palmer, Daniel Gildea and Paul Kingsbury, 2005. The Proposition Bank: A Corpus Annotated with Semantic Roles. Computational Linguistics, 31(1):71–106.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl26">Sameer Pradhan, Wayne Ward and James H. Martin, 2008. Towards Robust Semantic Role Labeling. Computational Linguistics, 34(2):289–310.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl27">Vasin Punyakanok, Dan Roth and Wen-tau Yih, 2008. The Importance of Syntactic Parsing and Inference in Semantic Role Labeling. Computational Linguistics, 34(2):257–287.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl28">Adwait Ratnaparkhi, 1996. Maximum Entropy PartOf-Speech Tagger. EMNLP ’96.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl29">Roi Reichart, Omri Abend and Ari Rappoport, 2010. Type Level Clustering Evaluation: New Measures and a POS Induction Case Study. CoNLL ’10.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl30">Philip Resnik, 1996. Selectional constraints: An information-theoretic model and its computational realization. Cognition, 61:127–159.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl31">Patrick Saint-Dizier, 2006. PrepNet: A Multilingual Lexical Description of Prepositions. LREC ’06.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl32">Anoop Sarkar and Daniel Zeman, 2000. Automatic Extraction of Subcategorization Frames for Czech. COLING ’00.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl33">Sabine Schulte im Walde, Christian Hying, Christian Scheible and Helmut Schmid, 2008. Combining EM Training and the MDL Principle for an Automatic Verb Classification Incorporating Selectional Preferences. ACL ’08.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl34">Yoav Seginer, 2007. Fast Unsupervised Incremental Parsing. ACL ’07.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl35">Caroline Sporleder and Linlin Li, 2009. Unsupervised Recognition of Literal and Non-Literal Use of Idiomatic Expressions. EACL ’09.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl36">Robert S. Swier and Suzanne Stevenson, 2004. Unsupervised Semantic Role Labeling. EMNLP ’04.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl37">Robert S. Swier and Suzanne Stevenson, 2005. Exploiting a Verb Lexicon in Automatic Semantic Role Labelling. EMNLP ’05.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl38">Kristina Toutanova, Aria Haghighi and Christopher D. Manning, 2008. A Global Joint Model for Semantic Role Labeling. Computational Linguistics, 34(2):161–191.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl39">Aline Vllavicencio, 2002. Learning to Distinguish PP Arguments from Adjuncts. CoNLL ’02.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl40">Dave Willis, 2004. Collins Cobuild Intermedia English Grammar, Second Edition. HarperCollins Publishers.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl41">Nianwen Xue and Martha Palmer, 2004. Calibrating Features for Semantic Role Labeling. EMNLP ’04.</bibl>
        <bibl xml:id="Bl42">Benat Zapirain, Eneko Agirre and Lluis Marquez, 2009. Generalizing over Lexical Features: Selectional Preferences for Semantic Role Classification. ACL ’09, short paper.</bibl>
    </listBibl>
</div>
